<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CSSU</title>
    <description>University of Toronto Computer Science Student Union</description>
    <link>https://cssu.ca/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://cssu.ca/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:18:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>CSSU Screening: The Martian</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Come one, come all! You’ve attempted surviving CS, now watch a man attempt to survive MARS. It’s gross and fun, but the popcorn will only be the latter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a night of intelllectual cinema and suspense. With a side of Toronto Popcorn Co. popcorn :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When: Friday, May 25th, 2018
Where: BA7321&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/events/2025009874415546/&quot;&gt;Click here for more Information!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://cssu.ca/events/cssu/2018/05/25/Martian-Movie-Night.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cssu.ca/events/cssu/2018/05/25/Martian-Movie-Night.html</guid>
        
        <category>cssu</category>
        
        <category>movies</category>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
        <category>cssu</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CSSU General Council Applications are Open (2018 - 2019)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you see yourself here, helping positively impact the CS community at UofT? Apply to be a CSSU general council member now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfb2jbi56SuOLxh6lwaDmdlUqjGU_0uhWRAcYHXR8vGLcDu_w/viewform?usp=send_form&quot;&gt;To Apply Click on this Link!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://cssu.ca/news/2018/05/17/general-council-applications.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cssu.ca/news/2018/05/17/general-council-applications.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Midnight in Morocco: CSSU Semi-Formal</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Come and celebrate with the Computer Science Student Union’s Semi-formal Dinner and Dance: Midnight in Morocco!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experience the charm of French-Moroccan cuisine as you dance in the antique candle-lit Berber room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With music courtesy of AI DJs (thanks to Rave and Crowdplay) and a human DJ too, this formal is the perfect way to get together with all your friends before PEY, graduation or just to celebrate the end of another fantastic year of school!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When: Thursday, March 29th, 2018
Where: Sultan’s Tent, 49 Front St E, Toronto, ON M5E 1B3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doors open at 7PM, Dinner will be served at 8PM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tickets: $45 on Eventbrite&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plus credit processing fees of $3.86&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Please note that there are no refunds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;LAST DAY TO BUY TICKETS IS THURSDAY MARCH 22nd at MIDNIGHT&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dress Code: Semi-formal attire&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food &amp;amp; Drinks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3-course meal (choices available on ticket)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 drink ticket from the bar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cash Bar is available&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;General Information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coat check will be provided&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Attendees 19+ must have valid ID to receive a stamp&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vegetarian, Vegan, and Halal options are available&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Non-CS students welcome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/cssu-semi-formal-dinner-and-dance-midnight-in-morocco-tickets-43506451969&quot;&gt;Click here to purchase your tickets!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For inquiries about allergies, accessibility or anything else, please email us at utcssu@gmail.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://cssu.ca/events/cssu/2018/03/29/Semi-Formal.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cssu.ca/events/cssu/2018/03/29/Semi-Formal.html</guid>
        
        <category>cssu</category>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
        <category>cssu</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CSSU Star Trek Screening</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We may have popcorn, we may have your favourite star trek episode on a big screen, and we might even make you live long and prosper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/events/171688480125267/&quot;&gt;Click Here&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://cssu.ca/events/cssu/2018/03/16/Star-Trek.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cssu.ca/events/cssu/2018/03/16/Star-Trek.html</guid>
        
        <category>cssu</category>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
        <category>cssu</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CSSU Election (2018 - 2019)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Its that time of the year to elect new executives for the CSSU! In addition to executive positions offered in past years we have added 4 new elected positions – Director of Social Events, Director of Academic Events, Director of Internal Relations and Director of External Relations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IMPORTANT DATES:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nomination Period: Wednesday, March 14th to Tuesday, March 20th&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Campaign Period: Wednesday, March 21st to Tuesday, March 27th&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Election Day: Wednesday, March 28th&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roya Shams will be the CRO presiding over this year’s elections. All other election announcements will be made on the official CSSU Facebook group by the CRO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information on each position and the election process please consult the &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2FF0lBW&quot;&gt;CSSU constitution&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in running for a position please fill out the nomination form &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2GoTwWj&quot;&gt;found here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions you can reach the CRO at roya.shams.zadeh.amiri@mail.utoronto.ca&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://cssu.ca/news/2018/03/14/elections.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cssu.ca/news/2018/03/14/elections.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CSSU x DCS Town Hall</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Have questions about POST? Wondering what resources are available for you? Want to know more about the CS program?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a conversation with several faculty members of the Department of Computer Science, including Francois Pitt, Danny Heap, David Liu, Estina Boddie and Beatrix Doma, this Friday March 2nd from 5PM to 7PM in BA1200! Pizza will also be served courtesy of the DCS, who are sponsoring this event!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is your chance to ask any questions you have about CS at UofT. This could include questions on courses, study spaces, research opportunities, or program requirements. Take this time to share any concerns effecting your experience and make your voice heard! Our objective is to generate discussion and gather input for the continued improvement of DCS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So get your questions ready and don’t forget to drop by!
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/events/782684001933439/?ti=cl&quot;&gt;Click Here&lt;/a&gt; to be directed to the event.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://cssu.ca/events/cssu/2018/03/02/Town-Hall.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cssu.ca/events/cssu/2018/03/02/Town-Hall.html</guid>
        
        <category>cssu</category>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
        <category>cssu</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Recruitment Breakfast</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Come out to BA3200 on 27/02/18 from 11 AM - 1 PM for a recruiter breakfast! Bring your resume, chat with recruiters from several companies and enjoy some FREE coffee and pancakes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies Attending:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flybits&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accenture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FDM Group&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Intel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Loopio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More companies to be announced! Keep checking back for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://cssu.ca/events/cssu/2018/02/27/Recruitment-Breakfast.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cssu.ca/events/cssu/2018/02/27/Recruitment-Breakfast.html</guid>
        
        <category>cssu</category>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
        <category>cssu</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Platterz x CSSU Hackathon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hungry for hacking? From on-demand delivery services, to predictive technology, food tech is changing the way we eat. On February 16th in BA3200, join Platterz and the CSSU for 24 hours as we get together to remix the food industry and find innovative solutions towards improving food-related tech. Come meet other food and tech-lovers, bring an idea to life, eat a bunch of pizza, and have a lot of fun! The details: Your hack should be related to food, and should be as creative as you like! There are prizes for hacks related to supporting health, generating leads for a particular service, and the use of a chatbot. It should be a functioning app or prototype. No cost to participate. Unlimited pizza &amp;amp; drinks! The prizes: Lots of awesome tech prizes, including: PS4, Xbox One, VR headset, drone, headphones, nerf gun and more. Opportunity for an internship at Platterz. Who’s invited: Any and all U of T students in teams of 1-4. All skill sets are welcome, from developers, to UX/UI designers, to marketing experts and foodies! Please make sure each team member registers individually.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://cssu.ca/events/cssu/2018/02/16/Platterz-Hackathon.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cssu.ca/events/cssu/2018/02/16/Platterz-Hackathon.html</guid>
        
        <category>cssu</category>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
        <category>cssu</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CSSU Karaoke and Games Night</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome back! Its a new semester and the CSSU wants to welcome you to the new semester with video games and karaoke! Come out and play some board games, eat free food, sing some karaoke, jam out and have a spectacular time with your friends! Join us at Bahen Center in room 3200 at 6:30pm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://cssu.ca/events/cssu/2018/01/26/Karaoke-Games-Night.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cssu.ca/events/cssu/2018/01/26/Karaoke-Games-Night.html</guid>
        
        <category>cssu</category>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
        <category>cssu</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TorontoAI x CSSU - Neural Networks in TensorFlow</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The CSSU is proud to welcome TorontoAI to UofT! TorontoAI (torontoai.org) will be presenting a seminar on how to implement neural networks in TensorFlow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professor Sanja Fidler will also be in attendance to talk about some of her work in the field of AI. Learn more about what she does &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.utoronto.ca/~fidler/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is intended to be both a high level introduction as well as an exploration of applied techniques so consider bringing your laptop to follow along!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/torontoai-x-cssu-neural-networks-in-tensorflow-tickets-41406033561&quot;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to purchase tickets for this event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NOTE: Student ID will be required with tickets at the door. If you are not a student please &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/Toronto-AI/events/245997433/&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt; for alternative admission.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://cssu.ca/events/cssu/2018/01/18/Neural-Networks-Tensorflow.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cssu.ca/events/cssu/2018/01/18/Neural-Networks-Tensorflow.html</guid>
        
        <category>cssu</category>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
        <category>cssu</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
