<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CSSU</title>
    <description>University of Toronto Computer Science Student Union</description>
    <link>https://cssu.ca/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://cssu.ca/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 03:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 03:10:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>CSSU Update for 2019 A summary</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There has been many changes over the last few weeks as there has been a huge shakeup inside the CSSU. Below is a letter from the new interm-president Calvin Luo about the changes. Along with a second statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Statement 1:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;January 22, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear U of T Computer Science Community,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to update the community that on the 21st of December, David Ansermino officially tendered to the council his resignation as President of the CSSU. Apart from being President last term, David was also juggling the responsibilities of coursework and a full-time job. With these responsibilities increasing over time, he has since determined that he would be unable to give the CSSU the level of commitment befitting the position, and conceded his role on the executive team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this moment we have been advised by the ASSU not to hold a by-election for this position; as we must hold one near the end of the term for next years administration, spending time running a by-election (which takes 3 weeks) now and onboarding the individual would effectively leave the CSSU with almost no time to actively serve the community. This is also a sentiment shared amongst our Executive Council. As a result I, Calvin Luo, will be acting in the capacity of Vice-President and Acting President of the CSSU until further notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to take this opportunity to be as transparent as possible regarding the current status of the CSSU. It is no secret that this past term has been filled with turmoil - we have had resignations from our leadership, two by-elections, and a lack of events and communication. On top of that, budget talks with the department were ultimately not pushed through, hamstringing our e↵orts to run events in this term as well. Internal conflicts amongst the executive team hampered effective leadership, and without proper direction the General Council has become largely inactive. It is abundantly clear that reform needs to happen, and it needs to happen now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one, it is imperative for both Executive and General Council members to exemplify leadership, initiative, and transparency. The community deserves to know both what is going on inside the CSSU as well as the Department. Also, it is necessary to have a smaller council- with larger ones, we have experienced first-hand the difficulty of finding suitable meeting times and getting everyone on the same page. Lastly, it is undeniably important to interview General Council applicants, to ensure that only the ones with initiative and a passion for service are able to properly utilize the platform to embetter the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, I am wholly optimistic for the future. We have had the benefit of adding new members to our Executive team - we would like to welcome Ibrahim Hasan as our new Director of External Communications and Victor Li as our new Director of Social Events. They, along with our veteran members, have been invaluable in drafting up a new budget and event schedule for the Winter term, which we plan on submitting to the department for approval posthaste. I have full confidence in each and every member of our Executive team and their commitment to revitalizing the CSSU - and I believe that with an updated General Council, we will be able to best serve the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, I hereby announce the disbandment of the current General Council. We will be reforming it over the course of a week, and we expect it to come back leaner and more effective than ever. We will be interviewing applicants for the new General Council on a rolling basis, and will be looking for people who display initiative, drive, and a strong desire to serve the community. The form to apply can be found here, and we encourage anyone interested to fill it out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://bit.ly/2MskQWu&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, I would like to make clear the goal of this iteration of the CSSU, as well as the values we will be championing for the rest of the term. First and foremost, we are committed to reestablishing the CSSU as a stable operating body, and setting it up for success for future administrations. What this means is cutting down on ambitious projects in favor of investing in infrastructure and focusing on doing the things we do well. For example, we will be prioritizing the quality of the community events we host, instead of quantity. Our current communication channels will also be revamped to provide a more structured way for us, and future administrations, to both hear from and speak to the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of values, the words that come to mind are Transparency and Service. We are dedicated to improving the level of transparency the CSSU offers both in terms of our operations as well as the Departments, and we also want to make sure your voices are heardby us. We plan to align ourselves closer with the community, so that we can not only learn about current problems, but also work with the department to fix them. Lastly, we want to reiterate the importance of service - as CS students, we are all in this together, we all want whats best for each other, and we all have the power to make a difference for the better. To serve one another is a beautiful thing, and we want to provide a platform to turn altruistic efforts into reality.As I close I would like to reiterate that the CSSU holds, and will always hold, deep care and affection for the CS community, and an undying commitment to improving the undergraduate experience. We would love to have you join us on this mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calvin Luo,Vice President, Computer Science Student Union&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Statement 2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear CS Community,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to announce that I have just received the resignation of our Treasurer, Taylor Stinson. Taylor and I agreed that at this moment, the Executive Council of the CSSU should be filled with people involved with the community and dedicated to improving it. We also agreed that at this moment, with budgeting and funding talks with the department at stake, an experienced Treasurer is invaluable. To fill his position in the interim, I have appointed Borna Salman as Acting Treasurer. Many of you may know Borna for the fantastic job he has done as our community store manager; he has been directly responsible for expanding our selection, keeping our selling operations and tools smooth, and making sure our accounting is orderly. With his dedication to the CSSU, years of retail experience, and a shrewd eye for finance, we expect him to faithfully execute the responsibilities of his role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ASSU has also previously suggested that it would be beneficial to appoint an interim Vice President to provide a more stable leadership team. After deliberating with other members of the Executive Council, we have determined that this would be a worthwhile pursuit. I would thus like to welcome Ignas Panero Armoska to the Executive Council as our Acting Vice President. Ignas has previously been an immensely positive force on behalf of the CSSU during his tenure as a General Council member and Director of Social Events, and has continued to serve the community through other initiatives such as UofTHacks. There is absolutely no question about the level of dedication and passion he has shown, and we are happy to have him join our new team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, I am fully confident in our collective ability to effect the changes necessary in our community, and help improve the undergraduate experience. Stay tuned for exciting updates regarding our General Council!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regards,
Calvin Luo, Acting President&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://cssu.ca/news/2019/01/26/CSSU-Update-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cssu.ca/news/2019/01/26/CSSU-Update-2019.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>POST Statistics Breakdown</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The University of Toronto now uses the term ‘program’ in replacement of ‘POSt’, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;POSt ≡ program&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As many of you know, CS program admission is one of the most stressful things for new CS students at St. George. Every year since 2014, there has been a cutoff – an average of CSC165 and CSC148 marks – that determines the students who get into the program. There is some misinformation about why it exists and how it works. We hope here to give you a fuller picture, and as much data as possible to allow you to make informed decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main reason that we have rigorous admission requirements is a limitation of space, instructors, and TAs. The department lacks the resources to operate courses that can fit everyone who is interested. These bounds are the result of complex interactions between the Faculty of Arts &amp;amp; Science, the Department, and outside forces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The admissions process uses an in-stream/out-stream categorization system. When applying from highschool you are allowed to apply to the CS stream (CMP1). The CMP1 stream has a higher admission average than most and in turn offers mild leniency when applying to the program. What many applicants fail to understand is that you are not in the program until you apply and accept an offer after completing CSC148 and CSC165 (this is also why you are not charged deregulated CS Fees in your first year but “general” artsci fees). Beyond the students who are in-stream (CMP1), any students who has taken CSC165 and CSC148 are allowed to apply to the program. There are many students who explore CS courses, find that they enjoy it, and decide to pursue it as one of their fields of study. As seen in the chart below this make up a sizeable number of the overall applicants to the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department is taking steps to increase its faculty size and teaching capacity to try and accept more students, but the continuously increasing cutoff is only a reflection of the continuously increasing quality and competitiveness of students applying. The gist of how these cutoffs are calculated is basically such:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sort applicants in decreasing order of their averages (CSC148 &amp;amp; CSC165)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select top &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;n&lt;/code&gt; students, where &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;n&lt;/code&gt; is the number of spots in the program for the following year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admissions is split into two rounds, one following the close of the winter session and another following the close of the summer session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following chart was provided after requests to the department for more concrete information. This comparison is between 2017 and 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;overflow-x:auto; width:95vw;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;table cellpadding=&quot;2&quot; border=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
          &lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td colspan=&quot;6&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;2018 Admission statistics First Round&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td colspan=&quot;6&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;2018 Admission statistics Second Round&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td colspan=&quot;5&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;2017 Major + Spec. statistics&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
          &lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Minor Only&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Data Science&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Major + Spec.&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Minor Only&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Data Science&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Major + Spec.&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;First Round&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Second Round&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
          &lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Apply&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Offers&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Apply&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Offers&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Apply&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Offers&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Apply&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Offers&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Apply&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Offers&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Apply&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Offers&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Apply&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Offers&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Apply&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Offers&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;CMP1&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;53&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;28&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;360&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;197&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;78&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;35&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;24&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;146&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;49&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;268&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;148&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;57&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Other&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;218&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;81&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;85&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;428&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;122&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;186&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;79&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;63&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;253&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;62&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;411&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;155&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;272&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;55&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Total&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;271&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;96&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;113&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;788&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;319&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;264&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;114&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;87&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;399&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;111&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;679&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;303&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;329&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;65&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(This is the first year of Data Science, a joint program with CS and Stats.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is typically a predetermined number of positions available in the program each year (Major + Spec., see table below). The total number of offers should exceed that slightly as not every offer is accepted. Transfer students have also been excluded above. Note that not all students in CMP1 decided to pursue a CS Major/Specialist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following is the number of applications versus offers for the major and specialist program over the years as taken from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.cs.toronto.edu/program/ugrad/admission.htm&quot;&gt;department site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;overflow-x:auto; width:95vw;&quot;&gt;
&lt;table cellspacing=&quot;3&quot; cellpadding=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
   &lt;tbody align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;
       &lt;tr&gt;
           &lt;td&gt;&lt;b&gt;Year:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
           &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;2014&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
           &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;2015&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
           &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
           &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;2017&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
           &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;2018&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
       &lt;/tr&gt;
       &lt;tr&gt;
           &lt;td&gt;&lt;b&gt;Number of Applications:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
           &lt;td&gt;537&lt;/td&gt;
           &lt;td&gt;647&lt;/td&gt;
           &lt;td&gt;841&lt;/td&gt;
           &lt;td&gt;828&lt;/td&gt;
           &lt;td&gt;981&lt;/td&gt;
       &lt;/tr&gt;
       &lt;tr&gt;
           &lt;td&gt;&lt;b&gt;Number of Admissions*:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
           &lt;td&gt;453&lt;/td&gt;
           &lt;td&gt;539&lt;/td&gt;
           &lt;td&gt;567&lt;/td&gt;
           &lt;td&gt;475&lt;/td&gt;
           &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;TBA&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
       &lt;/tr&gt;
   &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There used to be the cutoff averages for these years posted on the department site. The department now feels that this is not a beneficial indicator for students. If one year of applicants were to do especially poor (or CSC165 and CSC148 were especially difficult) the cutoff for that year would sink. If another were to do especially well it would rise. While many may take comfort in having a definite goal, these historical cutoffs may not represent the current requirements for the program. The cutoff is basically the average of the student with the lowest marks to get into the program at that given time. If you would like to know more please get in touch with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would like to thank Francois Pitt and the department for their help in giving us these numbers and their permission to release them to the public. Francois also talked on last years &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/room-2250/s1e2-the-pitt-questions&quot;&gt;Room 2250 Episode&lt;/a&gt; about the program if you want further information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we get more information, we will update this post. We hope this has helped you and if you have any feedback feel free to let us know. Feel free to open a PR on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cssu/cssu.ca/blob/draft/_posts/news/2018-10-24-POST-numbers.md&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to contribute :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://cssu.ca/news/2018/10/24/POST-numbers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cssu.ca/news/2018/10/24/POST-numbers.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>University of Toronto Game Design and Development Club (GDDC)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Game Design and Development Club aims to bring together anyone interested in the design and development of interactive electronic entertainment. They host events and provide a forum where programmers, artists, musicians and writers can join together to discuss and create video games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.utgddc.com&quot;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt; |
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/utGDDC&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; |
&lt;a href=&quot;info@utgddc.com&quot;&gt;Email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://cssu.ca/clubs/2018/10/23/utGDDC.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cssu.ca/clubs/2018/10/23/utGDDC.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>clubs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>University of Toronto Computer Graphics Club (UTCG)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UTCG aims to explore computer graphics from a computer science and artistic perspective. We hold research talks, workshops and social events for anyone interested in computer graphics! Whether you’re interested in graphics programming or want to brush up on your graphic design skills, everyone is welcome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://utcg.club&quot;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt; |
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/UTComputerGraphics&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; |
&lt;a href=&quot;utcomputergraphics@gmail.com&quot;&gt;Email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://cssu.ca/clubs/2018/10/23/UTCG.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cssu.ca/clubs/2018/10/23/UTCG.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>clubs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TechXplore</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;TechXplore is a University of Toronto student-run club that operates to provide students with tutorial-style hands-on learning for tech-based projects (i.e. Java, Python, R Programming, 3D Modelling &amp;amp; Printing, etc.). We host a series of events and training modules to help our peers develop a passion and skill-set to succeed in technology-inclined industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;contact.techxplore@gmail.com&quot;&gt;Email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://cssu.ca/clubs/2018/10/23/TechXplore.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cssu.ca/clubs/2018/10/23/TechXplore.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>clubs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Review of Undergraduate Computer Science (RUCS)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Review of Undergraduate Computer Science (RUCS) is an open-access, non-archival publication based at the University of Toronto that features the best of research work conducted by undergraduate students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rucs.ca&quot;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt; |
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/RUCSjournal&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; |
&lt;a href=&quot;rucsuoft@gmail.com&quot;&gt;Email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://cssu.ca/clubs/2018/10/23/RUCS.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cssu.ca/clubs/2018/10/23/RUCS.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>clubs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project Include (PI)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A non profit student initiative aimed at making coding accessible to all children, irrespective of their financial status, race, gender, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/projectincludeskule/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; |
&lt;a href=&quot;info@projectinclude.ca&quot;&gt;Email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://cssu.ca/clubs/2018/10/23/PI.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cssu.ca/clubs/2018/10/23/PI.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>clubs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>National Society of Black Engineers - Uoft Chapter (NSBE)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With more than 23,000 members worldwide, the National Society of Black Engineers (NSBE), founded in 1975, is the largest student-managed non-profit organization in the world. NSBE has more than 300 chapters on college and university campuses and more than 80 Alumni Extension chapters and interest groups in the U.S., Africa, Asia, Canada, Europe and the Caribbean.   The National Society of Black Engineers Uoft Chapter offers its members leadership training, professional development, mentoring opportunities, career placement services and more. NSBE Uoft also supports students outside of the engineering field who may operate in the engineering industry such as students who may work in computer science, humanities, life sciences, social sciences and so many more. NSBE believes in fostering a safe place for minority students who contribute to all aspects of the industry.  Follow us on facebook at https://www.facebook.com/NSBEUofT and on instagram and twitter at nsbeuoft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/NSBEUofT&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://cssu.ca/clubs/2018/10/23/NSBE.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cssu.ca/clubs/2018/10/23/NSBE.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>clubs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CSSU Blog - Week 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the second post of the CSSU Blog our weekly blog series with news, events, tips and everything else you need to know. For those of you who don’t know what this is you can find my first post &lt;a href=&quot;https://cssu.ca/news/2018/10/05/CSSU-update.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. As always thank you for taking the time out of your day to read this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Tis the season for midterms, assignments, and all the “wonderful” things that make up university life. While the weather has been cooling down, your coursework has been heating up and the CSSU has been busy making plans for lots of events and activities to give you a break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all of these tests, assignments, and coursework, you can feel overwhelmed. Make sure that you’re taking care of yourself; stress is serious. You can visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://cssu.ca/heath&quot;&gt;our health page&lt;/a&gt; for health resources and if you ever need a place to relax the CSSU is here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, let’s get into this week’s content:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;news&quot;&gt;News:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The CSSU is having its first open General Member Meeting of the year on Thursday Oct. 18th from 5pm - 6:30pm. The executives and general council  will be speaking about the work they have been doing this semester, we hope you’ll come out and make your voice heard. (There will be a full recap written by a guest writer in next week’s post so look forward to it)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The University of Toronto is currently reviewing all Convocations and a group of CS students have spearheaded a campaign to get the university to add a CS convocation similar to Rotman’s and the DCS’s 50th anniversary convocation. Current Signature Count (as of writing) is 444 signatures. You can read the full petition and sign &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.change.org/p/university-of-toronto-convocation-review-committee-let-cs-graduate-together&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Also leave your written comments with the committee on their site &lt;a href=&quot;https://uoftgc.wufoo.eu/forms/u-of-t-convocation-review-2018/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Konrad Group is offering two $2,000 scholarships to third and fourth year Computer Science students. The Digital Innovation Scholarship is open to undergraduate students in the computer science field who are interested in pursuing a career in digital technology. The Women in Technology Scholarship is designed for female undergraduate Computer Science student who’s interested in pursuing a career in digital technology. For more information visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.cs.toronto.edu/news/events/konrad_awards_2018-19.htm?DateTime=636758244000000000&amp;amp;PageMode=View&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Applications are due Oct 22, 2018.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In more scholarship news, the Canada Chinese Computer Association Scholarship in Computer Science is taking applications. For requirements and application details &lt;a href=&quot;https://bb.teach.cs.toronto.edu/t/canada-chinese-computer-association-scholarship-in-computer-science/582&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;. Applications are due Wed Oct 31, 2018.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google has a bunch of scholarships open for &lt;a href=&quot;https://bb.teach.cs.toronto.edu/t/more-google-scholarships/931&quot;&gt;applications&lt;/a&gt;. (Way too many for me to list so I’m going to save time and let you click the link to read it).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In non-scholarship news, for the sci-fi/Frankenstein fans, St. Michael’s College is having a week long series of events celebrating the 200th anniversary of Frankenstein (the book). From Oct 24-31 2018. For more details &lt;a href=&quot;https://bb.teach.cs.toronto.edu/uploads/default/original/1X/e4eea7838388a039b3474deebe98d750863f2002.pdf&quot;&gt;read the poster&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;events&quot;&gt;Events&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;upcoming-events&quot;&gt;Upcoming events:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oct 16th 12-2pm DCIL Talent Tuesday - Data Science: Department of Computer Science Innovation Lab is hosting this event where you can meet industry and startup mentors who can help guide you in your future career plans.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oct 16th 7pm CSSU Screening: Black Mirror: We’re going to be screening Black Mirror with popcorn so get some friends and come down to relax and enjoy some scary episodes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oct 17th 12-2pm CS Grad School Info Session BA2185: If you are interested  in doing grad studies in CS join Associate Professor and Associate Chair, Graduate Studies in the Department of Computer Science Angela Demke Brown and Matt Medland, Assistant Professor, Teaching Stream and Managing Director of Professional Programs (MScAC) for an in-depth info session on what Grad School is and how to make your application stand out.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oct 18th 5pm - 6:30pm CSSU General Meeting: Read Item 1 on the news report.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oct 23rd 6pm Ethics of AI Film Series WALL-E, Centre for Ethics, 200 Larkin Street: Personally WALL-E is one of my favorite films and if you have not seen it you should. The Center of Ethics is screening the film with Mark Kingwell from the Philosophy Department to talk about the Ethics of AI and how they apply in the film. For more info &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethics.utoronto.ca/ethics-of-ai-film-series/&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-of-the-week&quot;&gt;Tip of the week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can SSH onto the teaching labs from your personal computer with your username and password. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teach.cs.toronto.edu/using_cdf/ssh.html&quot;&gt;Click Here&lt;/a&gt; for details on how to set it up (Putty is brilliant for windows). This is really useful for when you need to run your code on the teach machines (for 2nd year and above courses where compiling and running C code on windows is a pain) without needing to be in the lab. For the veteran users who know that already, there are actually multiple servers that you can ssh into if the main one is really busy (really helps in high traffic times like when a CSC369 or CSC320 assignment is due or MATLAB). yelp and jwebb are the servers and all you need is to ssh into the regular teach.cs.toronto.edu and from there ssh (server_name), remember to use the machines responsibly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;interesting-links&quot;&gt;Interesting Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If on the off chance that UOFT is ever closed, you can check the status of the campus at any time &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.utoronto.ca/campus-status&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We have updated and uploaded a new office code &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1FI7NU-B-lHJq7C7jKqhQ2XCHG-a4njXFYUH-EVZEGJE&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; feel free to give us some feedback!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading, and I hope you enjoyed it. If you have any feedback, feel free to email us, comment on the facebook/reddit post, or come to the CSSU to talk to us (or to this week’s General Meeting).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great week!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://cssu.ca/news/2018/10/14/CSSUpdate-Week-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cssu.ca/news/2018/10/14/CSSUpdate-Week-2.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CSSU Blog - Hello World</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So hopefully you’ve been getting into the swing of things, whether you’re a first year or finishing up your degree on behalf of the CSSU I hope you’ve been had a great first month back. The CSSU has also been busy this past month prepping lots of great events and things for you to make the most of your experience here at UofT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Anujan and I’m this year’s CSSU webmaster, this past summer myself along with Clara wrote the CSSU’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cssu.ca/firstyearcs&quot;&gt;First Year Guide to CS&lt;/a&gt;, we’ve received a tremendous response from students both incoming first years and current students. We’ve heard the feedback and hope that we can update and build on that guide going forward and create more great content for all CS students. This series of news posts are a part of that effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal in these posts is to give you a “one-stop” shop for all the DCS, UofT and interesting news that will hopefully make you aware of whats happing and will happen. Information is spread out through a lot of different locations and hopefully I can bring some really interesting things to your attention. While this won’t be fully comprehensive, I think I can try my best :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This “Blog” will hopefully be published every week on cssu.ca with the CS news you need to know about, upcoming events and tips and tricks. In upcoming posts I hope to add lots of interesting content whether guest writers, interviews and maybe a space for readers like you to submit your content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, let’s get into the content:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;news&quot;&gt;News:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From the &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.cs.toronto.edu/news/current/U_of_T_s_Michelle_Craig_wins_prestigious_OCUFA_teaching_award.htm&quot;&gt;CS Department&lt;/a&gt;, Professor Michelle Craig has been named one of Ontario’s most outstanding university teachers by the Ontario Confederation of University Faculty Associations (OCUFA) for the 2017-2018 year. Professor Craig has taught many CS courses at the undergrad level such as CSC343 and CSC209. She is also one of the creators of the PCRS C modules which is used in CSC209 to supplement learning in the course though preparatory videos and exercises. If you see her around please congratulate her on this wonderful achievement.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The University of Toronto is currently reviewing all Convocations and a group of CS students has spearheaded a campaign to get the university to add a CS convocation similar to Rotman’s and the DCS’s 50th anniversary convocation. You can read the full petition and sign &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.change.org/p/university-of-toronto-convocation-review-committee-let-cs-graduate-together&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Konrad Group is offering two $2,000 scholarships to third and fourth year Computer Science students. The Digital Innovation Scholarship is open to undergraduate students in the computer science field who are interested in pursuing a career in digital technology. The Women in Technology Scholarship was designed for female undergraduate Computer Science student who’s interested in pursuing a career in digital technology. For more information visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.cs.toronto.edu/news/events/konrad_awards_2018-19.htm?DateTime=636758244000000000&amp;amp;PageMode=View&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While it seemed to have been a slow CS news week here at UofT, I thought I would share some “recent” achievements of CS undergrads to possibly inspire you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Samin Khan (4th Year CS Student) this summer won Microsoft’s Imagine Cup along with his teammate from UOIT. Imagine Cup is a worldwide competition where students pitch new ideas and products that can help people. Read more &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.cs.toronto.edu/news/current/global_innovation_competition.htm?DateTime=636707014200000000&amp;amp;PageMode=View&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for Nina’s Interview with him about his experience, inspiration and whats he’s doing next.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Along with him another undergraduate student who’s done some cool things this summer is Lana El Sanyoura (finished her 3rd year and will being her final year in 2019 after PEY) (also full disclosure Lana was a member of the CSSU last year as noted in the article). She interned at MIT-IBM Watson AI Lab within IBM Research in Cambridge, Massachusetts working with leading AI researchers and professors. You can read her interview by Nina &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.cs.toronto.edu/news/current/U_of_T_computer_science_undergrad_interns_at_MIT-IBM_Watson_AI_Lab.htm?DateTime=636718267800000000&amp;amp;PageMode=View&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;events&quot;&gt;Events&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;upcoming-events&quot;&gt;Upcoming events:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oct 9th 4-5pm BA7231 How to Network Workshop: Need help navigating the basics of networking and meeting new people? Learn how in a session led by U of T’s Mentorship and Peer Programs. Pizza will be provided. Register &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.cs.toronto.edu/news/events/Talking_to_New_People_Registration__Oct_9.htm&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oct 10th 10am-1pm Pancake Breakfast: Its a CSSU tradition at this point come down and have some delicious free pancakes (either as breakfast, lunch or snack). New this year Apple Cinnamon Pancakes (They actually taste good)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oct 10th 1-3pm BA5250 Microsoft Office Hours: Microsoft is coming back to UofT and they’re holding office hours where you and go talk to them about anything from recruitment, job experience and lots of other great things. Register &lt;a href=&quot;http://clnx.utoronto.ca&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oct 16th 12-2pm DCIL Talent Tuesday - Data Science: Department of Computer Science Innovation Lab is hosting this event where you can meet industry and startup mentors who can help guide you in your future career plans.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For a full list of events visit the CSSU Facebook Page or the DCS &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.cs.toronto.edu/news/events.htm&quot;&gt;events page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-of-the-week&quot;&gt;Tip of the week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your in the CS POST you get 600 pages a year of free printing in the labs at Bahen (and only Bahen) note the printers are on the 2nd and 3rd floor labs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;interesting-links&quot;&gt;Interesting Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teach.cs.toronto.edu/usage/usage.html&quot;&gt;See which labs are free and which are not&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mirror.utoronto.ca/&quot;&gt;If you need to update/get a mirror for fast Linux installations UofT hosts mirrors of all the popular Linux flavors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope this was a great read and informative to you. If you have any feedback feel free to email us, comment on the facebook/reddit post or come to the CSSU to talk to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Thanksgiving from all of us at the CSSU!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://cssu.ca/news/2018/10/05/CSSU-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cssu.ca/news/2018/10/05/CSSU-update.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
